CELERINO HERRERA

WHO AM I

.Net Developer with 15 years working for desktop and web applications. I've had the opportunity to perform bug fix and create software for a wide diversity of business types: accounting, healthcare, point of sales, government, security, warehouse and others.

SKILLS (YEARS)

```
C# (15) Web API(4) MVC.Net(6) Asp.Net(10) .NetCore(1)
WCF(4) WPF(1)
TSQL (15) SSIS(2) SSRS(4) Oracle(2) Postgre(1)
Javascript (10) AngularJS(4) TypeScript(2) React(1)
NodeJS(1)
Agile/Scrum (10) Kanban(2) Waterfall(2)
CI/CD JetBrains - TeamCity (4) Team System (4)
Source Control TFS(6) VSTS(2) GIT(4) SVN(4) VSS(4)
Reporting SSRS(6) Jasper(1) Crystal(2) Telerik(2) VFP(2)
Access(2)
Java (2) servlets, jsp, hibernate
Python (1)
Go (1)
```

EXPERIENCE

BairesDev (Remote Developer

2018 - 2020

Remote Developer for two years, also an aid to the recruitment department performing technical interviews.

Kapsch TrafficCom:

FullStack developer working with AngularJS, TypeScript, Angular-React, RabbitMQ, docker, WCF, WebAPI.Net, SQL and Oracle server.

Project iterrupted due to COVID-19 in Buenos Aires, Argentina.

TicketNetwork:

Desktop and SQL Developer for the main Point of Sale Client-Server system. Tasks usually were bug fixing over legacy code, but also created new controls for improving the processing PDFs internally for the server application.

1 month of training at client facilities in Connecticut.

Contpaq (Contract Developer) 2017 - 2018

C#.Net and .Net Core developer working with Lucene.Net, SQL Server. Contpaq is a company with one of the most successful accounting software in México.

Tata Consultancy Services (Nearshore Developer) 2014 - 2017

Beside my services as a .Net Developer for two projects, I also performed a lot of interviews for new candidates, coaching activities for new members and managment activities growing two teams.

CIGNA:

Data Specialist. Performing data manteinance tasks and report creations using SSIS and DTS Packages. 1 month of training at Connecticut headquarters.

ABSG:

Fullstack Developer. AngularJS, Typescript. HTML/CSS with MVC and Restful API on backend. Full test covarage for backend in NUnit framework. Analysis of user activities related to Healthcare sectors: practices, pharmacies, nurses, patients, diagnostics.

Quarter meetings at client facilities in Frisco, TX.

Tiempo Development (Nearshore developer) 2010 - 2014

Tiempo Development is an outsourcing company. There I've worked on these projects.

ATA Retail:

Fullstack developer. Maintenance to legacy code for the biggest system of ATARetail, made in MSAccess 2003 (VBScript). Migration of MSAccess modules to web applications using MVC.Net and Bootstrap.

Profit Keeper:

VB.Net developer. Bug fix to legacy code for internal CRM.

Tripwire:

RegEx engineer and Senior Developer. Creation of regular expressions for the parser of TripWire Log Center (TLC). Bug fixing for the client and server application. Total use of TDD and Continuous Integration using Jetbrains' Teamcity. Also in charge of analysis for FIPS compliance.

Bufete de tecnología y Soluciones Avanzadas 2007 – 2010

BTS is a company focused to fulfill government needs. I have worked as a developer for systems many government needs.

Frontend and Backend developer for desktop applications in C#, ASP.Net, Reporting Services, Infragistics controls.

Release master for ClickOnce distribution.

Implementation and installation of our systems in the Honduras' government computers.

Equipos y Sistemas (EyS) 2004 - 2006

Developer for new products and bug fix for legacy code in Java, Visual FoxPro and Visual Basic.

Creation of a client-server application using web services for synchronization of points of sales between stores in order to have real time queries of Inventory and Sales Reports (this was fully configurable for any kind of ODBC data you wanted to synchronize).

- Improve Visual FoxPro Applications as architect and developer. C# architect and developer for new system EysCommercia.Net (still active).
- ASP.Net developer for Baja California's government Health care dependency "Seguro Popular"
- Develop login controls for use of biometrics instruments (voice recognition and digital fingerprints).

EDUCATION

BS Computer Engineer

UABC (Universidad Autónoma de Baja California

2003_2009

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native

ENGLISH: Professional working proficiency